<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>12mins on This is EggCellent</title>
    <link>/tags/12mins/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 12mins on This is EggCellent</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 12:39:22 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/12mins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Minute Omelette in a Mug</title>
      <link>/post/2017/12/13/2-minute-omelette-in-a-mug/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 12:39:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017/12/13/2-minute-omelette-in-a-mug/</guid>
      <description>Time of preparation    Preparation Cook Total     3 mins 2 mins 5 mins    Ingredients  2 to 3 eggs 1 Tbsp of ham or precooked meat, diced 1 Tbsp of salsa 1 Tbsp shredded cheese olive oil or cooking spray salt and pepper  Instructions  Coat your mug with olive oil or cooking spray. Add eggs to mug and whisk together with a fork Add diced meat, salsa, cheese, salt and pepper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A warm and creamy porridge</title>
      <link>/post/2017/12/13/a-warm-and-creamy-porridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 12:39:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017/12/13/a-warm-and-creamy-porridge/</guid>
      <description>Time of preparation    Preparation Cook Total     1 mins 10 mins 11 mins    Ingredients  1&amp;frasl;2 cup rolled oats (not instant). 1 1&amp;frasl;3 cup full cream milk (or almond milk or coconut milk if you prefer). 1&amp;frasl;4 teaspoon ground cinnamon. pinch salt. 1 tablespoon pepitas (preferably activated),optional. 2 tablespoons coconut flakes, optional.  Instructions  Combine oats, milk, cinnamon and salt in a small saucepan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avo-Tahini Toast</title>
      <link>/post/2017/12/13/avo-tahini-toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 12:39:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017/12/13/avo-tahini-toast/</guid>
      <description>Time of preparation    Preparation Cook Total     10 mins 0 mins 10 mins    Ingredients  1 teaspoon fresh lemon juice Dash of kosher salt 1&amp;frasl;2 ripe peeled avocado 1 (1-oz.) slice whole-grain bread, toasted 3 grape tomatoes, quartered 2 pitted kalamata olives, chopped 1 hard-cooked large egg, peeled and sliced 1 teaspoon tahini (sesame paste)  Instructions  Combine juice, salt, and avocado in a bowl, mashing with a fork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Banana Smoothie</title>
      <link>/post/2017/12/13/raspberry-banana-smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 12:39:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017/12/13/raspberry-banana-smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Time of preparation    Preparation Cook Total     5 mins 0 mins 5 mins    Ingredients  3 very ripe bananas, cut into chunks, frozen 1&amp;frasl;2 cup frozen raspberries 1 cup SILK almond milk 1&amp;frasl;2 cup fresh orange juice (preferably no sugar added) 2 tablespoons raw honey (more to taste, if desired)  Instructions  Place all of the ingredients in a blender and pulse until smooth, about 30 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Blackberry Chia Pudding</title>
      <link>/post/2017/12/13/simple-blackberry-chia-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 12:39:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017/12/13/simple-blackberry-chia-pudding/</guid>
      <description>Time of preparation    Preparation Cook Total     2 mins 10 mins 12 mins    Ingredients  1 Tbsp chia seeds 1 Tbsp plain yoghurt 2 Tbsp blackberries 0.25 tsp maple syrup a tiny splash of vanilla extract  Instructions  Place the chia seeds, yoghurt, milk, maple syrup, blackberries, and vanilla into a jar (for the large batch I find a one-liter wide-mouth mason jar works perfectly) and stir well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>